This is The Power Broker. It's a
Pulitzer Prize winning biography of the
master builder of New York, Robert
Moses, uh written by Robert Caro. Uh and
this book is a beastly 1,200 pages long.
It's so long. Uh I actually, when I was
an undergrad, I had a class where this
was the assigned reading, and instead of
actually reading this book, I just opted
to drop the class and not read it. And
it's a real shame because it's a classic
of the city planning literature. Uh and
as a professor, I feel double shame
because I've just not read this book,
and it seems like I should. Uh and in
fact, uh President Barack Obama says, "I
think about Robert Caro and reading The
Power Broker back when I was 22 years
old and just being mesmerized. I'm sure
it helped shape how I think about
politics." So, Barack Obama read it when
he was 22 and became president. I did
not read it when I was 22 and did not
become president. So, what does that say
about this book? Powerful stuff, worth
reading.
And I'm making a series of videos where
I read through this book. It's a real
long series, and I want you to come
along with me. So, at the very least,
subscribe so you can see my periodic
updates as I get through this book. I'll
summarize the chapters that I read as
well as provide my thoughts, but really
what I would love you to do is go to
your local bookstore, pick up a copy of
this bad boy, or download an ebook, or
whatever, and read along with me. Uh
we'll share our thoughts in the
comments, and I'll post things. Uh it'll
be great. Um so, the first few chapters
of this aren't too long, so expect my
next video pretty quick here. Um but
I'll I'll wait a little bit to to give
you a uh a chance to get a copy of the
book. But again, subscribe, follow
along. It's going to be fun. We're going
to get through this beast together.
The Power Broker. All right, see you in
the next one.